IMRAN SAYEED

Operation Coordinator Import / Customer Services



+923009206749

imran.sayeedno1@gmail.com

S 0092 3072999840

https://www.linkedin.com/in/imra n-sayeed-a56511b9

Karachi-Pakistan

ABOUT ME

Highly motivated trained and qualified professional of working as a coordinator and Customer Service experience and strong work ethic. Confident and enthusiastic with a friendly outgoing personality. I can work on my own initiative or as part of a team. I communicate well with fellow staff. I have excellent leadership skills to do my work responsibilities and duties.

CAREER OBJECTIVE

After 19 years of experience in Customer Service in reputable companies, I'm looking for a long term position where I can utilize my experience and excellent background to add a value to my next reputable company, thus add value to my ability and further expand my career.

EDUCATION

MBA (Banking & Finance)

Passing year: 2008

Muhammad Ali Jinnah University,

Karachi Pakistan

Post Graduate Diploma (Business Administration)

Passing year: 2006

Muhammad Ali Jinnah University,

Karachi Pakistan

Bachelor of Commerce

Passing year: 2001

Karachi University | Karachi, Pakistan

SKILLS

Industrious
Self-Motivated
I I I I I I I I I I I I I I I I I I I
Flexible
Problem Solver
Results Driven
Fast Learner
Details Oriented

EXPERIENCE

COORDINATOR 2021 - 2022

Aluminum Products Company (Alupco) 2021 | Dammam-Saudi Arabia

- Generating Sales Order in ERP and transfer / Released in the system.
- Item wise and Order wise Sales orders distributed in the departments.
- Daily maintaining & preparing Plant Reports of Production of all departments.
- Checking materials and their availability to inform the procurement department.
- Timely and accurately Documentation to conduct day-to-day operationwork as per sales intention and customers' requirement.
- Closing Sales Order in ERP system which completed on a daily basis.
- Preparing KPI's of the department monthly basis.
- Preparing Monthly Letter Report, Score-Card and Budget Vs Actual reports.
- Daily maintaining attendance sheet of the different department and sending to HR.
- Coordinating with other departments and arranging meetings as per Plant Manager.
- Prepare tracking report to check late orders and balance orders.
- Perform filing and data entry as required.
- Providing administrative support.

OPERATION COORDINATOR / CR CONTROL OFFICER C/S 2015 -2021

CSFC United Marine Agencies Pvt Ltd (Shipping & Logistics) | Karachi, PK

- Supervising/managing importing counter and solving consignees and forwarding agent problems at the time.
- Communicating with principal, port of loading, customs, terminal operator, and local consignee regarding over all import matters.
- Replying all the received inquiries from different counterparts and ports with a close follow up.
- Controlling documentation of shipments, meetings with international agents / counterparts and appointments with customers.
- Following up, recovering, and monitoring all the long idling containers.
- Sending arrival notices to customers prior to arrival of vessel.
- Issuing the invoices payment, delivering orders, and gate pass invoices.
- Checking refund cases as per shipping line tariff decided and forwarded it to the department's account.
- Preparing final invoices in local system and online principal system.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Resolved more than 700 pending cases in one and half month as a Detention Coordinator in United Marine Agencies of Hyundai Shipping Line.
- Cleared the backlog of pending issues, as an Assistant, (Renewal of contract employees) of more than 2000 out of 9000 employees and ensured that HR Department is performing smoothly.
- Trained the new employees of Customer Care Department regarding use of SAP (CRM & ISU), S.O.P'S & TAT'S of complaint.
- Due to my good customer services and resolvingcomplaints before TAT many of the customers want to meet me or remember due to my quality of services. This positive gesture or attitude of the customers make me motivated to achieve company goals.
- Have dealt with many customers inpressure during system failure.
- Received several, Man of Match Awards / Shields in K-Electric Interdepartmental Cricket Tournaments.
- Proposed the idea to Departmental Heads for Usage of SMS Caster Software for providing information to the customers also to keep them updated regarding outages / information and use of this software in other issues as well.
- Recovered the outstanding dues approx \$650,000 in 2018-2019.

LANGUAGES

- English
- Urdu

INTEREST

- Playing Cricket
- Watching Sports
- Net Surfing

REFERENCE

Will be provided on demand.

- Issuing index sheets to all concern parties.
- Issuing and delivering orders to clearing agents.
- Strong following up of long idling containers which staying in the terminal or customer premises to get back the empty containers to our vard.
- Closely monitoring and following up the outstanding dues due to Demurrage /Detention and recovering the dues against customers.
- Updating and checking free days of the shipment in the system.
- Updating timely M&R charges of damaged containers in the system.

SENIOR CUSTOMER CARE OFFICER (Team-Leader)

2009 -2015

K-Electric | Karachi, Pakistan

- Responsible for actively ensuring the relation of the company's customer base which includes promoting the company's existing customer.
- Participating in developing a policies and S.O.Ps related to customer service.
- Collecting and analyzing the data to monitor the level of customer service.
- Handling complains and resolving issues related to customer satisfaction.
- Attempting to persuade customer to reconsider cancellation.
- In depth knowledge of the Billing.
- Resolving and lodging complaints as per SOP.
- Using SMS caster software to keep the customers updated regarding outages / information and other complaints.
- Providing and helping Customers Installments in the old dues to pay the bills easily and regularly as per company policy.
- Providing and Educating customers about Rebate policy of the company to boost the collections of overdue payments.
- Handling and facilitating Customers in Power Failure Complaints and make sure our team will resolve the complaints urgently.

DATA ANALYST

2006 -2009

K-Electric | Karachi, Pakistan

- Managing and monitoring all activities regarding billing and administrative issues of whole cluster / region.
- Preparing & compiling regional reports and forward it directly to the managers.
- Managing and maintaining data of all employees.

ASSISTANT

2004 -2006

K-Electric | Karachi, Pakistan

- Managing different activities regarding HR issues.
- Resolved all pending backlog issues regarding contract employees and renewal letters of more than 9000 employees on monthly basis.
- Planning, managing, and optimal utilization of material and HR.
- Managing all employees' data as per requirement of HR department.

CERTIFICATES

GDPR Staff Awareness course

Certified from GAC

Six months short diploma (I.T & M.S Office)

Aligarh Institute

Certification of Advance Excel.

Viftech-KE

Certification of Managerial Competencies & Customer Care.

Certification of Soft Skills (PSTD) for Managing Customers.

Certification SAP ERP (CRM & ISU Module).

ALUPCO Emergency Plan and Fire Prevention Training